Neil Sanathara

Anaheim Hills, CA (714) 399-6756 NeilSanathara@gmail.com

PROFILE

Systems Engineer with over eight years of experience in IT support. Accustomed to collaborating with multiple departments to provide assistance with IT tools and applications. Able to handle multiple projects simultaneously while providing the highest level of service and quality in a timely manner. Knowledgeable in user interfaces, testing, and debugging processes.

SKILLS AT A GLANCE

- Solar Winds & Engine Service Desk Pro
- Server 2012 & 2008 R2 Datacenter
- Exchange Servers
- Teamviewer, Ulta VNC, & LogMein
- Office 365 Administrator

- Symantec Ghost & FOG Project Servers
- ShorTel VOIP & Group Policy
- VMware vSphere 5
- Salesforce
- Stood in for network engineer for 3 months.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Systems Engineer at Advanced Computer Technology in Austin TX

Jun.-Nov 2019

- Provide remote and in person support for multiple small businesses and county utilities.
- Configure various systems based on security requirements of individual companies.
- Install hardware upgrades and create user profiles based on company requirements.
- Provide support for custom software used by regional water utility company.
- Maintain and manage servers, desktops, laptops, printers and VOIP phone systems.

Systems Support Engineer at LRES Corp. in Orange CA

2014-2017

- Complete company upgrade of new VMware vSphere Servers 2008 R2 and 2012 R2.
- Manage Active Directory, Exchange Server, and Office365 accounts for over 200 users.
- Conduct routine maintenance and upgrades for servers, company technologies, and user interfaces.
- Provide remote support for satellite offices located in Phoenix, Arizona and Tulsa, Oklahoma.
- Image computers with Symantec Ghost 11 and Symantec Ghost 15.
- Organize tickets by need and interact with employees to solve technological problems quickly.

Computer Tech at Digitron IT Staffing Solutions in LA & Orange County

2008-2018

- Diagnose, research, and resolve problems, including but not limited to software and server crashes, hardware failure, software updates, and data recovery.
- Asses clients' needs to build company-specific computers and software portfolios.
- Provide ongoing support and routinely follow-up to ensure optimal performance.

Desktop Support Specialist at Interface Rehab Inc. in Placentia CA

2012-2013

- Learned internal billing software (Rehab Optima) quickly on the job.
- Provided in person and remote support to over 3000 users across 80 satellite offices.
- Use remote software to provide support and ticketing system with progress tracking.
- Maintain servers and create backup regularly in compliance with regulations.
- Traveled between facilities and corporate to set up computers, printers, network, and update hardware and software. Set up FOG Project server to put a multitude of computers in the field within 2 weeks.

EDUCATION

A.A. Computer Science, Fullerton College